A Guide to the Cumberland County (Va.) Judgments, 1749-1902
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Cumberland County (Va.) Judgments, 1749-1902
The Library of Virginia
1115581-1115583, 1115585-1115587, 1147665-1147714, 1155464-1155585
80.1 cu. ft. (185 boxes)
Cumberland County ( Va.) Circuit Court
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in shipments of court papers from Cumberland County.
Historical Information
Cumberland County was formed in 1749 from Goochland County.
Scope and Content
Cumberland County (Va.) Judgments, 1749-1902, contain civil cases in which justice was administered on the strictly formulated rules of common law. The majority of cases in this record series relate to matters of debt.
Arrangement
Chronological (Cases filed within each box by month and year they were resolved.)
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Cumberland County (Va.)--Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Civil procedure--Virginia--Cumberland County.; Decisions--Virginia--Cumberland County.; Debt--Virginia--Cumberland County.; Public Records--Virginia--Cumberland County.
Geographical Names:
Cumberland County (Va.)--History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Judicial records--Virginia--Cumberland County.; Local government records--Virginia--Cumberland County.
Contents List
- Judgments 1749-1750 (Barcode 1147665)
- Judgments 1751-1752 (Barcode 1147666)
- Judgments 1753-1754 (Barcode 1147667)
- Judgments 1755 (Barcode 1147668)
- Judgments 1756-1757 (Barcode 1147669)
- Judgments 1758-1759 (Barcode 1147670)
- Judgments 1760-1761 (Barcode 1147671)
- Judgments 1762 (Barcode 1147672)
- Judgments 1763 Mar-Jul (Barcode 1147673)
- Judgments 1763 Aug-1764 March (Barcode 1147674)
- Judgments 1764 Apr-Dec (Barcode 1147675)
- Judgments 1765 (Barcode 1147676)
- Judgments 1766-1767 Mar (Barcode 1147677)
- Judgments 1767 April-Dec (Barcode 1147678)
- Judgments 1768 Jan-Jul (Barcode 1147679)
- Judgments 1768 Aug-1769 May (Barcode 1147680)
- Judgments 1769 June-1770 Jul (Barcode 1147681)
- Judgments 1770 Aug-1771-Apr (Barcode 1147682)
- Judgments 1771 Jun-1772 May (Barcode 1147683)
- Judgments 1772 Jul-Dec (Barcode 1147684)
- Judgments 1773 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1147685)
- Judgments 1773 May-Jul (Barcode 1147686)
- Judgments 1773 Aug-Sep (Barcode 1147687)
- Judgments 1773 Oct-1774-Mar (Barcode 1147688)
- Judgments 1774 Apr-Dec (Barcode 1147689)
- Judgments 1775-1778 June (Barcode 1147690)
- Judgments 1778 July-1779; [1770-1779] (Barcode 1147691)
- Judgments 1780-1783 July (Barcode 1147692)
- Judgments 1783 Aug-1784 Mar (Barcode 1147693)
- Judgments 1784 Apr-Dec (Barcode 1147694)
- Judgments 1785 Jan-Jun (Barcode 1147695)
- Judgments 1785 Jul-1786 Apr (Barcode 1147696)
- Judgments 1786 May-Oct (Barcode 1147697)
- Judgments 1786 Nov-1787 Apr (Barcode 1147698)
- Judgments 1787 May-Aug (Barcode 1147699)
- Judgments 1787 Sep-1788 Apr (Barcode 1147700)
- Judgments 1788 May-Dec (Barcode 1147701)
- Judgments 1789 Jan-Sep (Barcode 1147702)
- Judgments 1789 Oct-1790 June; [1780-1789] (Barcode 1147703)
- Judgments 1790 July-1791 August (Barcode 1147704)
- Judgments 1791 Sep-1792 (Barcode 1147705)
- Judgments 1793 (Barcode 1147706)
- Judgments 1794 Jan-Jul (Barcode 1147707)
- Judgments 1794 Aug-1795 Mar (Barcode 1147708)
- Judgments 1795 Apr-Dec (Barcode 1147709)
- Judgments 1796 Jan-Jul (Barcode 1147710)
- Judgments 1796 Aug-1797 Jul (Barcode 1147711)
- Judgments 1797 Aug-1798 Jul (Barcode 1147712)
- Judgments 1798 Aug-1799 Jul (Barcode 1147713)
- Judgments 1799 Aug-Dec; [1790-1799] (Barcode 1147714)
- Judgments 1800 Jan-July (Barcode 1155464)
- Judgments 1800 Aug-Dec-1801 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155465)
- Judgments 1801 Apr-Aug (Barcode 1155466)
- Judgments 1801 Sept-Dec-1802 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155467)
- Judgments 1802 Apr-June (Barcode 1155468)
- Judgments 1802 July-Oct (Barcode 1155469)
- Judgments 1802 Nov-Dec--1803 Jan-May (Barcode 1155470)
- Judgments 1803 June-Oct (Barcode 1155471)
- Judgments 1803 Nov-Dec--1804 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155472)
- Judgments 1804 Apr-July (Barcode 1155473)
- Judgments 1804 Aug-Nov (Barcode 1155474)
- Judgments 1805 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155475)
- Judgments 1805 Apr-July (Barcode 1155476)
- Judgments 1805 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1155477)
- Judgments 1806 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1155478)
- Judgments 1806 May-July (Barcode 1155479)
- Judgments 1806 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1155485)
- Judgments 1807 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1155480)
- Judgments 1807 Apr-July (Barcode 1155483)
- Judgments 1807 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155484)
- Judgments 1808 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1155481)
- Judgments 1808 May-Dec (Barcode 1155482)
- Judgments 1809 Jan-July (Barcode 1155486)
- Judgments 1809 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1155487)
- Judgments 1810 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1155488)
- Judgments 1810 May-Sept (Barcode 1155489)
- Judgments 1810 Oct-Dec (Barcode 1155490)
- Judgments 1811 (Barcode 1155491)
- Judgments 1812 Jan-May (Barcode 1155492)
- Judgments 1812 June-Dec--1813 Jan-Feb (Barcode 1155493)
- Judgments 1813 Mar-Dec (Barcode 1155494)
- Judgments 1814 (Barcode 1155495)
- Judgments 1815 Jan-July (Barcode 1155496)
- Judgments 1815 Aug-Dec--1816 Jan-July (Barcode 1155497)
- Judgments 1816 Aug-Dec--1817 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1155498)
- Judgments 1817 May-Aug (Barcode 1155499)
- Judgments 1817 Sept-Dec--1818 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1155500)
- Judgments 1818 May-Aug (Barcode 1155501)
- Judgments 1818 Oct-Dec--1819 Feb-Apr (Barcode 1155502)
- Judgments 1819 May-Sept (Barcode 1155503)
- Judgments 1819 Oct-Dec (Barcode 1155504)
- Judgments 1820 Jan-May (Barcode 1155505)
- Judgments 1820 June-Sept (Barcode 1155506)
- Judgments 1820 Oct-Dec (Barcode 1155507)
- Judgments 1821 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1155508)
- Judgments 1821 May-Aug (Barcode 1155509)
- Judgments 1821 Sept-Dec--1822 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155510)
- Judgments 1822 Apr-May (Barcode 1155511)
- Judgments 1822 June-Aug (Barcode 1155512)
- Judgments 1822 Sept-Oct (Barcode 1155513)
- Judgments 1822 Nov-Dec--1823 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155514)
- Judgments 1823 Apr-May (Barcode 1155515)
- Judgments 1823 June-July (Barcode 1155516)
- Judgments 1823 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1155517)
- Judgments 1824 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155518)
- Judgments 1824 Apr-May (Barcode 1155519)
- Judgments 1824 June-July (Barcode 1155520)
- Judgments 1824 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1155521)
- Judgments 1825 Jan-May [A-L] (Barcode 1155522)
- Judgments 1825 May [M-Y]-Aug (Barcode 1155523)
- Judgments 1825 Sept-Dec (Barcode 1155524)
- Judgments 1826 Jan-May (Barcode 1155525)
- Judgments 1826 June-Sept (Barcode 1155526)
- Judgments 1826 Oct-Dec (Barcode 1155527)
- Judgments 1827 Jan-May (Barcode 1155528)
- Judgments 1827 June-Sept (Barcode 1155529)
- Judgments 1827 Oct-Dec (Barcode 1155530)
- Judgments 1828 Jan-Feb (Barcode 1155531)
- Judgments 1828 Mar-May (Barcode 1155532)
- Judgments 1828 June-Aug (Barcode 1155533)
- Judgments 1828 Sept-Dec (Barcode 1155534)
- Judgments 1829 Jan-May [A-R] (Barcode 1155535)
- Judgments 1829 May [S-W]--Sept (Barcode 1155536)
- Judgments 1829 Oct-Dec (Barcode 1155537)
- Judgments 1830 Jan-May [A-O] (Barcode 1155538)
- Judgments 1830 May [P-Y]--July (Barcode 1155539)
- Judgments 1830 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1155540)
- Judgments 1831 Jan-July (Barcode 1155541)
- Judgments 1831 Aug-Dec--1832 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1155542)
- Judgments 1832 May-Dec (Barcode 1155543)
- Judgments 1833 Jan-June (Barcode 1155544)
- Judgments 1833 July-Dec (Barcode 1155545)
- Judgments 1834 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1155546)
- Judgments 1834 May-Dec (Barcode 1155547)
- Judgments 1835 Jan-May (Barcode 1155548)
- Judgments 1835 June-Dec (Barcode 1155549)
- Judgments 1836 Jan-Aug (Barcode 1155550)
- Judgments 1836 Sept-Dec--1837 Jan-Apr (Barcode 1155551)
- Judgments 1837 May-Sept (Barcode 1155552)
- Judgments 1837 Oct-Dec--1838 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155553)
- Judgments 1838 Apr-Dec (Barcode 1155554)
- Judgments 1839 Jan-July (Barcode 1155555)
- Judgments 1839 Aug-Dec--1840 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155556)
- Judgments 1840 Apr-Dec (Barcode 1155557)
- Judgments 1841 Jan-July (Barcode 1155558)
- Judgments 1841 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1155559)
- Judgments 1842 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155560)
- Judgments 1842 Apr-Aug [A-I] (Barcode 1155561)
- Judgments 1842 Aug [J-W]-Dec (Barcode 1155562)
- Judgments 1843 Jan-May [A-H] (Barcode 1155563)
- Judgments 1843 May [I-W]--June (Barcode 1155564)
- Judgments 1843 July-Aug [A-M] (Barcode 1155565)
- Judgments 1843 Aug [P-W]-Dec--1844 Jan-Feb (Barcode 1155566)
- Judgments 1844 Mar (Barcode 1155567)
- Judgments 1844 Apr-Dec (Barcode 1155568)
- Judgments 1845 Jan-July (Barcode 1155569)
- Judgments 1845 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1155570)
- Judgments 1846 Jan-July (Barcode 1155571)
- Judgments 1846 Aug-Dec--1847 Jan-Mar (Barcode 1155572)
- Judgments 1846 Oct-Dec--1848 June--1849 Feb (Barcode 1115587)
- Judgments 1847 Apr-Dec--1848 Jan-Feb (Barcode 1155573)
- Judgments 1848 Mar-Dec (Barcode 1155574)
- Judgments 1849 (Barcode 1155575)
- Judgments 1850 (Barcode 1155576)
- Judgments 1851 (Barcode 1155577)
- Judgments 1852 (Barcode 1155578)
- Judgments 1853 (Barcode 1155579)
- Judgments 1854 (Barcode 1155580)
- Judgments 1855 (Barcode 1155581)
- Judgments 1856 Jan-Aug (Barcode 1155582)
- Judgments 1856 Sept-Dec--1857 (Barcode 1155583)
- Judgments 1858 (Barcode 1155584)
- Judgments 1859 (Barcode 1155585)
- Judgments 1860-1871 (Barcode 1163727)
- Judgments 1860 (Barcode 1115581)
- Judgments 1861 (Barcode 1115582)
- Judgments 1862-1864, 1866 Jan-May (Barcode 1115583)
- Judgments 1866 Aug-Dec (Barcode 1115585)
- Judgments 1867-1902 Broken Series (Barcode 1115586)
- Judgments 1867-1872 (Barcode 1163776)
- Judgments 1872-1884 (Barcode 1163728)
- Judgments 1873-1880 (Barcode 1163777)
- Judgments 1881-1893 (Barcode 1163778)
- Judgments 1885-1889 (Barcode 1163729)
- Judgments 1890-1898 (Barcode 1163730)